uh magical and when it comes to business
and balancing
that that threw us for a whole Loop we
thought we'd be able to have a baby
it'll be fine you know we just give him
a grape and a bottle and we could sit
here and continue to do what we love to
do and it doesn't apparently work like
that in the model that we got
so he's like listen you're going to pay
attention to me at all times you going
to look me in the eye even when I'm
sleeping I want you to make ey come
so he's quite uh I don't know how we
thought we were going to have a quiet
kid cuz we're both kind of personalities
so it's he's condensed version of both
of us like I remember seeing him I was
like wow I am a real a-hole if that's
how I act like
wow but he is precious um the balance is
in we believe in integration so he is
there I've done podcast he's on my lap
I've been feeding babies falling asleep
I'm like keep and I'll be back I go put
him down like he's part of our life like
all of his stuff is here I got little
Matts in the corner from yeah jungle jym
Matts like you know we don't hide that
we have a baby and he's a part of our
life um I believe we lost a lot of
business because of it a lot of business
like I know for a fact in the first 30
days we lost $40,000 worth of business
because of it whoa people they had one
contract it was great everything's good
they're like come on in and and see us
and sit down and talk and questions in
there and tell me about this motherhood
thing oh mhm and later on it was a
friend of mine who was in the business
who invited us into bed and speaking to
him and only to realize he's like yeah
the guy didn't think you'd be able to
manage it I'm
like I love my baby but yeah I wouldn't
have it any other way you know yeah I I
I could say that I've had to make those
calls a few times I've been lucky you
know because I just tell people straight
up I'm a single father he's coming with
me he's coming with me into the the
boardroom I'm like here holding him you
know and uh he's you know at the time he
was on my lap and you know he couldn't
he wasn't old enough for him to to be on
his own so you know I just had to make
it work like it's beautiful
[Music]
welcome to the hustle Zone this is Ry
Perez AKA RP the god AKA The Wizard um
I'm owner and founder of bow tie
creative uh we donate free websites to
entrepreneurs with
disabilities so um yeah today is a
really good day every day on the hustle
zone is a good day but this is a
especially a good day because we have um
my my guest that I've known for quite
some time and you know he cracks me up
because the other day he had uh I was he
I was working and literally had me
watching um he was on his balcony and
had me watching a
hawk there was a hawk
and he had annotations as well like you
know cuz the hawk was just sitting there
looking for food and then he was
circling the hawk he's like look there's
a hawk you know so he that was pretty
funny but you know um all uh Jokes Aside
uh this is a brother that um he's an
entrepreneur he also has a beautiful
family and he has a a family business
where him and his wife work um and um
they have a a marketing company and uh
he's done so much great things so I'm
going to let him uh uh let you all know
what what he's accomplished but um from
the bottom of my heart this this man is
like a brother to me um there was few
questions that I had in regards to
business and you know he was just a
phone call away I gave him a call and
you know he literally changed my life
overnight you know we're we were we were
laughing today talking about scheduling
and how important it is to schedule and
you know people that are in the design
or in the marketing industry I I I asked
him um I asked him a question in regards
to um charging Discovery and Discovery
is pretty much what you do before you
before you actually accept the job and
he gave me a lot of insight on that so
you know he's a really smart man well
accomplished he was on
tedex um he he his company is wedge 15 I
mean he's been on TV his wife's been on
TV they have a beautiful baby boy I I
just I'm so happy to to have on my show
today Ricardo McCrae how's it going my
friend oh you
are I think you're muted here we go
thank you it's yeah it's amazing to be
here Ryan my man thank you like this is
an honor to be on your show the hustle
Zone well thank you for for for for
so the first question that we normally
ask you know because most people uh
would get mad at me if I don't ask you
but you know so what is your story you
know where did you start and where are
you
now as it relates to business I guess
um my business
bug got lit real early it's been like a
couple Generations uh my grandfather my
great-grandfather had a company in
Trinidad which is where I'm from
Trinidad and Tobago and I was being
groomed to take over that business in
Trinidad uh before I got sent up to
Canada to go to school and this is where
I am now and
about so was doing that in Trin was a
watch and jewelry and repair business
and when I came up here about uh within
a year or so I had opened my own company
I was 18 that was the first business I
opened called rhr student painters and
uh it blew up man like within
3 months I had 16 employees like it blew
up uh I still have the little
clipping from the newspaper like we
wrote a little something about ourselves
and sent it in and oh we trying to pay
for our way through University and help
us raise money and like they loved it
wrote the story about us and the phone
didn't stop ringing after that and it
was just like it totally made our summer
and that's how I got to University was
uh was from that hustle like that was it
you know uh went on to do all kinds of
stuff at school studied art at school
fine art painting drawing sculpture
Graphics uh was on student council did
black
homecoming uh got elected to student
body rep for the arts department you
know worked five jobs while I was going
to school full-time CU I couldn't find a
full-time job I was like [ __ ] I might do
four part-time jobs that'll add up I'm
like long as I'm working 40 hours a week
uh rode a bicycle through the winter
like I didn't have a car so I I I bought
a bike
my I've just listened to myself say this
not I'm like that insane so so I
couldn't buy a car I couldn't afford a
car so I bought like a $1,000 bicycle
with my oap money I said this going to
be my baby I bought a really nice bike
as mountain bike and I rode it
everywhere at bring it into class and
everything and people were just like you
can't bring this into the school I'm
like well I'm not locking this outside
cuz I can't afford to lose it so I said
I used to tell them I said if I'm in a
wheelchair would you tell me I can't
come in and they're like no I said well
this consider this my wheelchair I was
like okay and I was the only person
allowed to bring it into classes like
I'd be like right into class put it next
to the professor up at the Blackboard
and go sit down in the hall I'm like I
need to see my bike at all times I'm
like or I'm dropping your class like
that was my
that was my thing everybody's like who's
this guy I'm like whatever dude I'm like
this is what I got to do I got to go to
a job as soon as I leave here a got time
but uh I was on a tight schedule but uh
you know I learned a lot from that uh
then went into sales in Tech from Future
Shop to moving to Toronto to then
working in a tech company being a
project
manager then moving
to Worldcom MCI the largest internet
provider in the world doing corporate
sales for them did that for a number of
years
uh really learned about the internet how
it worked uh from the people that
actually made the internet like there
was a guy who's in her office Vince Surf
and if you Google him you'll see he's
one of the three people that invented
the Internet like he was hanging out at
the water cooler and I'm like what's up
VIN he's like what you doing he's eating
his apple pie and I'm
like these people it's like ridiculous
ridiculous sort of experience
and yeah left
that uh because I need to get back to
creativity and art like I walked away
from a six-figure job in 2000 like that
was what like 15 years ago was making
six figures and I was like yeah I got to
go make art like that's my contribution
to the world and
my best friend at the time was passing
with cancer and I would talk to him and
he told me his biggest regret in life
was not finishing his Jazz album And
That Shook Me To The Core you know
you're looking at a man with a
six-year-old son and he's like I'm like
what do you regret in life knowing
you're going to die he's like I didn't
finish that jazz album said I want to
give an album to my son and say that
when
Daddy when you want to hear what Daddy
has to say listen to this he said I
can't do that so I knew at that point I
was going to die at some point for sure
and I wanted the things that I do and
the work that I do in the world to speak
for me so I
quit piss a lot of people
off good West indan family they quit a
good job you gag I resigned my manager
tore it up he's like you're not
resigning I was like well I will gladly
keep the checks but I'm coming back
after two weeks and uh yeah I'm still
friends with all these people on
LinkedIn to this day like but yeah I
left I went got myself an art studio
started painting started building
websites taught myself web design and
really started blending that's when I
really started pulling things together
and really
make branding of thing like I started
seeing the expertise from the corporate
world blended with my artistic and
project management experience of like
how do we give smaller and excuse my
voice I'm just getting over a cold here
but really giving the smaller business
person or the person with that project
that doesn't have a huge budget or a not
for-profit really giving them an
advantage in the world by leveraging
Tech and using that to compete at the
same level with with major major brands
and winning uh so I was very happy about
that because you know the World is Flat
today when it comes to Tech like you can
get in you can do something you know we
can do a podcast so so that's been that
did that for a dozen or so years and
then I met my
wife uh in of all places a tanning
salon hold on hold on hold on that's a
whole different
story
tanning yeah I was doing some work for
doing some design work for the
uh for the woman in the tanning salon
and she was busy or something that day
and like oh just talk to Ricardo for a
minute so I end up chatting with her
because we were killing time and
yeah but we went on one date then we
were like yeah let's be together forever
I was like okay that was
it
um that's another crazy story with
that's a separate story but yeah we met
in January of 2010 and within a year she
had resigned from her job uh started her
own business and uh
we'd some contract each other for about
a year and after that we created we got
married and then created wedge 15 which
is our current business uh and we've
been doing that ever since so
it's you know she would bring strategy
and I'd bring like design project
management creativity to the mix and
it's uh it's been fun man it's
been that's the super fast version
that's a super fast well you super fast
version start digging deep because I
mean you have what you find man there a
lot of lot of skeletons in these classet
you well the first skeleton I want to
bring up
um Ted X the conference you know yeah a
world renown uh uh conference that you
can pretty much go and you talk about
ideas Etc and you were invited to be a
part of that so tell me a little bit
about that
uh yeah that was a wild experience that
was November 14th last year uh probably
a year prior to that the organizer of
the confer reach conference reached out
to us and said we'd love for you to come
out and be the lead speakers at at our
tedex University of waterl we're like oh
that's a big one that's not just that's
not like a Ted Little X that's a Ted big
X like yeah we cuz it's it was on my
bucket list uh two years prior to that
um was on my honeymoon we were in France
hanging out for a minute and I saw a
pair of yellow leather shoes and I said
I'm going to buy these shoes uh and I'm
going to wear these on the tedex stage I
said when I do a TED talk I'm going to
wear these shoes and uh two years later
almost to the day I was on a tedex stage
with those
shoes it was it was
it was the day France got attacked that
was the day we did that Ted X talk it
was the day before and that
day two years prior we were in France
like around that same area it was just a
real surreal moment MH in between France
T like like the worlds were just you
know an inch away from each other and uh
it
was incredibly surreal to be there in
that moment moment creating It 2 years
earlier and then having attacks on
France at the same moment when you're
doing the thing that you know it was
just insane but that you know we prepped
for a year we had coaches and we had
practice and learned how to talk cuz my
wife and I did it together and it's one
of those things you very rarely see a
TED talk with two people and where to
get special permission from Ted because
they're like do not do two people go
it's not we're like no man it's what we
do and then we have to look at you know
we are two different styles you know she
is like quick and fast and you know blah
blah blah blah blah and Ricardo is a
little more chill I'm a little more you
know laid back in the cut and how do
those two people powerfully sit on stage
together without fighting for the
spotlight and
without you know how do you dance and
two people telling one story and
creating this narrative with two
different styles so we got a a
professional voice coach and acting
coach and you know Richard was amazing
with us uh and really taught us all this
other stuff about just forget about what
you're talking about just be and just
dance with the other person while you're
there it's not a competition but it's
more of support so it was really improv
of how do you if somebody says something
what do you say that's the next thing
and being in that moment and hundreds of
hours of
practice two weeks prior we had
everything practiced and we were like
don't like it threw it all out did
something else like was it
was it was an experience like that's one
of those Shining Moments in life where
that it's like that changed our life and
the way we did things moving forward so
it uh it was cool that was a cool
experience how did you feel you know in
being yeah at that moment how did you
feel on stage after like which which
which on stage after because I mean I I
would have you know I would have lost my
mind man it's it
was super
calm cuz you had practiced so much at
that point I'm like if I get up here and
I don't know what I'm talking about I'm
like well we go to find out you
know we're about to learn
today and it it's it's it was just super
calm it was like chill like me and you
talking like we knew what we needed to
convey we weren't concerned about what
we were saying we were concerned about
how we made people feel right and as
long as we made them feel
it what we said actually didn't matter
mhm and it worked so we just like it was
just like like by the time we got to
that stage we're backstage of people are
running around and they're tugging at
your stuff and there mics and people are
like wait go and there's like all this
like five people are buzzing around you
at all times and in the midst of it me
and looking at each other and we're just
like you ready like yeah like all right
let's do this and we're standing there
and someone's holding a door and they're
like and it's just like go go go go go
we're like right now they're like yeah
said all right go we just walked out we
looked at the people said all right and
it was like 50,000 people watching live
like it was six cameras the prompter
like people there 500 people in the
audience live like it
was ridiculous but it was it was pretty
calm actually how did you feel about
where you were in in that in that time
you know in terms of success yeah did
you feel that you've reached your
Plateau no it's like success is what
success you know that's the kind of
thing you talk about on your deathbed
I'm I'm just doing
stuff you know I'm writing my obituary
every day I'm like I'm not even like as
a joke like like I actually think about
this and I try to reverse engineer my
life and say what do I want people to
say about me if I were to drop dead next
week mhm what would I do this week if I
knew I was going to die next week like
life gets real crystal when when you
start to do that and it's even when
you're going through stress or you're
going
through uh anything like even back to
that Ted talk like we were you know
trying all types of stuff to make it
work and sound good and we could do this
and la and we threw it all out like
practiced it for 6 months nailed it then
went no we could do better than that and
threw it out because it wasn't coming
from the
heart and it was a simple we spoke to
Drew Dudley a good friend of ours who
has done like nine or 10 TED talks
and he said listen he's like talk to
your baby he's like if you died and this
was the only thing your baby could
see what do you want him to know and
that just made it easy like you just
like you know to being a conversation is
just
right there and just come from the heart
so we just my wife was 9 months pregnant
on stage wow like like all of us were
like right there like my little baby did
a TED talk like he was kicking we had
plans like what if her water broke on
stage like it
was yeah it was it was real we're like
we're going to finish this talk he said
so how did how did you guys synergize
like how did you two you know cuz I I I
know how that would feel to be on a
stage and then having to compete for you
know space and right it I'll I'll tell
you the exercise that really made a
difference for us we were in The Voice
trading with Richard uh and his company
called but free your
voice just Google free your voice. ca or
whatever it is and Richard Stewart and
the thing we did was he asked us to
close our eyes hold up our hands like
this and we had a little dowel like a
broomstick and you had two of them and
we just touch the ends of the broomstick
with our fingers like this so we're each
holding she's on that side I'm on this
side and he said both of you close your
eyes he said now I want you to move your
hands in any direction and I want you to
dance around the room and don't drop the
sticks and say Daredevil what do you you
know so it worked and the reason it
works is because you have to stop
relying on your thinking and start
relying on your heart and your grounding
and your
soul and once that is never wrong so
somebody has to push while somebody's
pulling and somebody's moving in a
different direction and leaning
backwards well you know and it's and we
moved around this room it was like 30 by
30 we dance through the whole thing we
maybe dropped it once or twice but I was
shocked that it didn't drop and it's
presenting yourself to that feeling of
dancing and knowing when to push and
when to
pull uh and trusting that it's going to
be okay your partner has your back like
you have to know that you have to be
like if I drop something they got this
if I go left they're going to go left
like what I'm going to do is the right
thing to do and not think about the
right thing but just know it's the right
thing and just be in that zone and that
exercise really got us to
stop what about this and isn't this will
sound good when oh it'll sound better if
I do this and it'll be more articulate
it's like yo let's like in the middle of
our Ted Talk people are laughing in the
audience and yelling stuff out and it's
you don't just go
sh you know you got to respond to that
and like you know what I mean like you
have to it's actually real so trust that
whatever we're saying in this
conversation is real and whatever
they're saying to me is real and that
it's always right like life doesn't come
scripted life is about being present so
that exercise got us to be in our bodies
and be rooted which allowed us to Just
Dance on stage by the time you got there
it's like yeah it's all good it's easy
peasy dude we made mistakes on stage
like we forgot pieces stuff got left out
nobody would ever know because the
feeling got
conveyed I'm not worried about oh I
should have said this line and if they
got the message I need to stop
talking so do you find that with you and
your wife wife working together uh did
that exercise help you moving forward
with your business and tremendously that
that whole experience
was like
massive
and I'll share this and I've never
shared this before with anyone like we
came off that
stage like you do 10 like this is the
high of the Hat you know what I mean
like yeah you're pregnant like this is
it this is all we ending the year the
whole thing and
within a few hours of coming off that
stage we get a call from my sister
saying my little 10-year-old nephew was
playing football and they took him off
the field in a Stretcher with a neck
brace and it's like life life happens
like that and you're
just like that's real and I'm like okay
we got to drop all of this stuff we got
to get there like what do you need
what's going on well like my little
10-year-old nephew can't be
paralyzed do you know what I mean and
it's it's
that that's how life comes there some
high and then how you How do you how do
you dance with that yeah because it's
it's not always about this you know the
the highs last for a second like months
and months of training you were on stage
I was like okay that's it it was done
like that was it I trained for 6 months
9 months for that like yeah it was more
training than it was stage time it was
you know what I mean like so it's and
then the reality of like family and
someone being hurt and he's perfectly
fine now but that's good that's that's
how life is man so it's it's
uh yeah I don't know if I answered your
question well no you did you did you
know just I guess the question was like
like did you and your your wife work
together um in the same way that you
were on what did it change us yeah so
after the way we did business the way we
did deals the way we
were in the dealers we both sit with a
client changed
[Music]
um the way we were in our relationship
changed or the there wasn't there wasn't
a need not that not that there was
competition but there was far less ego
in it for both of us it was about
let's I mean it was like a 1% ego in
things and it it like it went to zero
after that
so this I cuz I've I've been in business
with with uh I I let just put it out
there I was in in business with an
ex-girlfriend and I think that's what
people want to hear about let's get into
that for a minut
and and it's it's really hard to balance
right like even uh with my with with uh
Max fiance you know we were I asked her
to to be a part of the business and it
was really hard to manage because you
know when you're when you have your
business hat on you know you you kind of
approach things differently than you
would uh if you
were if you're not working together
right so
how yeah they long-term ramifications to
being an [ __ ] in business when your
partners in it with you that's
right you're like oh this could impact
uh later on tonight right okay it's uh
cuz like for me I know like when it
comes to business I'm straight shooting
and there's no emotions I just get
through it and so how did you and your
wife how have you held it together for
this
long radical honesty about everything
and putting the relationship first
before business at all times and
yeah the relationship comes first rad if
we doing it's it's it's and super honest
like we're doing something we come out
of that meeting it's always a how was
that for you how was that for you
and look you know when I was talking you
cut me off that's not a good
thing I get that you're excited but
don't finish my sentences
like that type of honesty like we do
that like all the time yeah and it was
like I mean it started off a little more
Rocky and you know over a few years it
it smooth out and we found ways to but
just really whatever those are the
little grits of sand that sit in your
shoe that if you don't say
something two three 5 years in all of a
sudden you're like this look I ain't
going with you every time I go outside a
whole set up and it's if you
can't it's sounds like it would be harsh
to say it but if the person if you two
have an agreement to say that to each
other you can totally say it and know
there's no repercussions right I mean
we'd have arguments and fights and this
I guess regular stuff you're not going
to not have that
but the the honesty thing really makes a
difference it's like we both agreed to
be honest I can tell you anything yeah
yeah yeah okay now I tell you something
and your Vex I'm like can't have that
that's like so you know what I mean so
it's like we would deal with that if if
we were dealing with a client thing and
all to go on Skype together with a
client to do training and we're having a
fight or we not talking in the house but
we got to go and perform and we go on
there do the thing when we finish we're
like okay everybody bye-bye all right I
still not talking to you you know what I
mean yeah but it's you know there were
time to do business and it's but the
personal piece always came first it was
always Paramount like we'd be working
and something would happen and I'm like
okay I'm not feeling this I'm like I've
done something to piss you off oh busy
I'm like nope stop everything I said we
get into the bottom of this and we would
spend 3 4 6 however long it took the
whole day would go by we talking about
it once that was finished then we can go
back to business but you can't do
business in my opinion on top
of any of that sand right when did you
realize you know cuz I I think that we
all have epiphanies especially when
we're working with other people um
there's that one moment where we're like
okay we got to be brutally honest with
each other because this is not going to
work out if we don't you know what was
your what situation happened with you
where you realized that it was Paramount
that you had to be more you had to have
that
disclosure we had that from day one in
when we we connected it
was we're both kind of blunt people uh
most kind like whoo y'all are like I'm
like yeah yeah there's something in your
face like take that
off like we're both kind of like that so
it's it's either you like it or you
don't and you know we went on one date
and I'm like in the middle of the
date was like listen I'm going to say
something and it could end this date
immediately like that's how I prefaced
it I said it could like we won't even
get the dessert like you'll just walk
off like it's it's and I'm like
would you like to spend the rest of your
life getting to know
me she said yes I went okay let's do
that and we were never apart since that
moment like we
were together every single day since
that point like within a month she like
packed up moved in people were losing
their [ __ ] they were like who is this
guy that you went on what you went on a
day like what what do you mean you
moving like it was like so from day one
we started we talked about race we
talked about uh money that was a tough
one you know let me see your bank
account you know it's like
what when hold on when did that
conversation come up you know let me see
because I mean that came up in about the
third month
um
because she had this impression that I
had way more money than I did and she
was like yo I'm going to quit my job and
I'm like I said are you sure you want to
quit your job she's like yeah I said
okay if you want to quit your job and
it's not working for you we'll deal with
it next thing I know she's calling me
like yeah I brought everybody in the
boardroom and uh I told them what I
thought of them and I'm coming
home it's like I'll see in a minute baby
all right you
know and uh yeah I was like okay and
like as we're talking about bills and
life and all this stuff
like it it it came up we be like look
how we going to do this I said I don't
know we going to make it happen and uh
yeah click click click see that's my
bank balance let me see yours and ego
like I'm shortcutting like days of
conversation and all that stuff but like
ego of kind let people know how much
money like you know men have to provide
I should be able and it's just like look
we got to do something because it's it's
uh it's not like that yet yeah and
that's just the reality of it I want it
to be and it's not like that today there
are times when it is and there times
when it isn't with entrepreneurship
there's cash flow so I've learned to be
calm throughout the dips and also be
calm throughout the Peaks like we've had
months the biggest month we've ever had
was six figures in one month and we've
also gone 10 months without a contract
like so yeah there's Peaks and valleys
so it's about remaining consistent and
doing great work uh through all of that
that's that's again radical honesty
putting your you go say look I I feel
like a punk you know just get it
straight up into it you know yeah and uh
being that vulnerable about it uh
allowed her to be honest allowed her to
open up
and that is what has really been a
foundation of our uh of how we do
business and stuff and we put
relationship first not not business
that's right like business will come and
go I said but we ain't leaving a other
so this comes
first so that that being said you know
when we fast forward you are parents you
have your firstborn child and uh this is
why I love folks this is why I love the
hustle Zone because every entrepreneur
has a different story but we all have
similar habits and especially when we
have children because I'm a single
father and to manage a business you know
where I'm managing a few different
portfolios at the same time and then I
have to take care of my son drive him to
school pick him up drop him off lunches
and and and and coals clothes clothes
you B it he gets into a fight or he gets
sick so now how are you uh how are you
uh and your wife managing you know being
entrepreneurs and then also being
parents
yeah that's that's a hard you know I
heard the whole thing before Oh once you
have kids your chance of success goes up
and d d d da I was like ah it sounds
good you know it's like I want to be a
dad like planned let's do this uh
pregnancy was Flawless textbook uh birth
not so much three days in labor planned
a home birth we ended up at a hospital
two days of Labor in a hospital and a
cesarian at the end and it's like I was
I actually have video of most of it and
pictures of the whole experience like in
the operating room and like Gloria just
was looking at the pictures the other
day and she's like what is that I'm like
those are your your insides that they
pull at the baby like I have like I
reached above the curtain and I was
shooting video of HD like I'm sitting
there like click click click doctor's
like what are you doing I'm like don't
look at me buddy eyes
Down Eyes on the B look at me
and uh the anesthesia like every I was
all of it
on like there was so much happening and
then capturing that you know so you can
go back and experience it later on uh
magical and when it comes to business
and balancing
that that threw us for a whole Loop we
thought we'd be able to have a baby
it'll be fine you know we just give him
a grape and a bottle and we could sit
here and continue to do what we love to
do and it doesn't apparently work like
that in the model that we got
so he's like listen you're going to pay
attention to me at all times you going
to look me in the eye even when I'm
sleeping I want you to make eye
cont so he's quite uh I don't know how
we felt we were going to have a quiet
kid cuz we're both kind of personalities
so it's he's condensed version of both
of us which like oh I remember seen him
I was like wow I am a real a-hole if
that's how I act I'm like wow
but he is precious um the balance is in
we believe in integration so he is there
I've done podcast he's on my lap I've
been feeding babies falling asleep I'm
like keep talking I'll be back I go put
him down like he's part of our life like
all of his stuff is here I got little
Matts in the corner from yeah jungle jym
Matts like you know we don't hide that
we have a baby and he's a part of our
life um I believe we lost a lot of
business because of it a lot business
like I know for a fact in the first 30
days we lost $40,000 worth of business
because of it who people had one
contract it was great everything's good
they like come on in and see us and sit
down and talk and questions in there and
tell me about this motherhood thing oh
mhm and later on it was a friend of mine
who was in the business who invited us
into Bid And speaking to him and only
realize he's like yeah the guy didn't
think you'd be able to manage it I'm
like
I love my baby but yeah I wouldn't have
it any other way you know yeah I I could
say that I've had to make those calls a
few times I've been lucky you know
because I just tell people straight up
I'm a single father he's coming with me
he's coming with me into the the
boardroom I'm like here holding him you
know and uh he's you know at the time he
was on my lap and you know he couldn't
he wasn't old enough for him to to be on
his own so you know I just had to make
it work like it's beautiful yeah life
had to make it work you have to accept
me if you want to do business with me
and and they wanted to do business with
me so but you still this this is how the
package comes yeah and it's I don't talk
after this time when if my baby like
it's it it pissed some people off and
you know I don't care like my family and
my relationship before my business like
and it's it's
uh their well like was good like we can
we going work this out whatever that
thing is whatever that hurdle is we're
going to get through it
uh but yeah it's integration like now
he's in daycare which is good it's been
a year in the next I don't know 16 days
or so he's going to be one you know and
it's like wow that just went fast can I
ask you a question no drop
question dropping your kid off at
daycare
entrepreneur cuz you know we are we're
superheroes we feel like we're
superheros we can do everything but then
when having to drop your your son or off
in care that to me had a lot of it like
any time I have to give him to somebody
else I feel a sort of way it's it's
massive guilt it is heart- rening and
he's crying and daddy and mommy and
you're
[Music]
like like that goes against nature to
give your baby away you know and it's uh
it's hard because you have to do it like
how else are you going to get work done
I can't sit here and play Google Gaga
with you all day you know you're going
to need milk in about two hours every
two hours you going to be awake all
night I'm like Daddy's got to work so
there's a point at which uh he's old
enough and big enough that he can go to
daycare and that's part of life things I
have to do that's hard in business
sometimes this is just one of those
things in life and relationship ship
where it's like no we feel that
e excuse me at an age and stage where he
can actually be with other people and
it's actually good for him and he's
ready to play with other kids and you
know it's a couple days of crying but
now he's good and he's happy
but most of the tears came from me and
his mama you know and it's just like
that's your baby like I I don't know how
to explain that to people who don't have
a kid and I heard people say this stuff
and you're all you're obnoxious parent
and and you know I'm that guy now I'm
just like listen some things you just
have to experience Carnival can't be
explained a baby cannot be explained
yeah sex cannot be explained these are
all things you just got to be like you
figure it out you just what you going to
just just you know you have a baby you
you'll understand people I want to talk
to I ain't got time to talk to you you
know what I mean like I got a 45 minutes
before my baby wakes up and talking to
you is so low on my priority list it
call me in August you know what I mean
I'm like it's it it it puts it lets you
know what's you understand productivity
like we've got wickedly productive and
because of it like I know this is how
many hours I have he's coming home at
this time I'm doing this it's he's
asleep now and I'm like got to do the
dishes I got to finish this proposal I
got to do some designs cuz he wakes up
like he's not taking extra sleep
45 minutes I'm up so whether you want to
take a shower wash the dishes or do a
podcast he will be up in 45 minutes
govern yourself accordingly so you you
you get to be way more productive with
way less time uh and it put way more
restrictions and rituals and you know
before we were kind of way too laxed and
yeah so it's that's people like always
oh you upset and I'm like no not upset I
don't miss anything this is just my new
normal yeah and and the pain comes when
you try to fight it yeah oh I wish I
wish I could still go out on a Friday
night I'm like I'm home with my baby on
a Friday night like I couldn't care what
club is happening yeah you know I mean
I'm like it's it's that love you know
like I it's that when Malcolm was born
for me it was just the love that I had
for cuz people would come up to me and I
was I went to Victoria my friends were
like man
I don't know how you do it you know it's
almost like they think that that having
a child is babysitting I mean no it's
not babysitting it's like I love this
human being so much I will cut your
throat for my baby do you understand
me he runs things he's running things
and the only way like love is so
powerful like it it doesn't like when
you tell people what you do for a baby
it just doesn't make sense like you're
not going to sleep for a year like you
don't even understand what that means
like I tell people
this sleep deprivation is illegal as a
form of torture around the world like
you in Guantanamo Bay you can't not let
people sleep like you can't arrest
people and not put them in bail and not
let them sleep like you have to let
people sleep all parents go without
sleep your baby's up you're like every
two hours you're going to be woken up
every hour he didn't sleep like he's
still not sleeping through tonight
tonight he'll be awake seven times
tonight
like he's just going to wake up every
hour or two and got to hold him how you
doing all right back to
bed in an hour he'll be up again like he
was just going to be up and we've tried
the sleep training we've tried the
swaddle the blah they let him cry it out
we did it for 21 straight days the kid
scream oh that's horrible I said you
want to kill me I'm like what my baby
scream for two hours while I'm 10 ft
away from the baby it's like who's
benefiting from this I'm like my kid is
red in the face at 3:00 in the morning
as he's been screaming since 2 yeah he's
like pick me up I'm
like you know so it's you have what you
have and this is my new normal and I'm
grateful for it and I don't want to
change a damn thing that's right except
except the sleep I could I would I'd pay
money for sleep
right I understand I mean like it's a
phase cuz you're you're going to get
past that phase but sleep those like
just I know we're a little bit off topic
here but like it just the uh leaving
your kid in the room I tried that and
that's torture for the kid I I just had
to just do I had to just pick him up and
hold him you you know uh a lady told me
she's like you can't give your kid too
much love because there's going to be a
point of time where they just they're
like peace bye see you later it's it's
not for a long time it's it's you have
moments you have one year of him being a
baby and now he's he's ready to walk and
run and it's like he's no longer a baby
he's a toddler right and that baby stuff
is done so I'm glad I had all that time
to be with him uh losing all those
contracts here's the upside I got to
beat my baby every day for a year like
with him with him like no daycare like
247 I'm with my like
that's how much how much would you pay
for that like 40 Grand done
you know what I mean like whatever like
whatever we went through that whole year
doesn't matter it was 100% worth it and
yeah they'll be gone soon and it's they
moments it's like Liv in the Moment Like
This is what's important and I wouldn't
trade it for anything man
it's that kid shape is shaping my future
everything I do is through and for him
all my projects I'm like I I I weigh it
against how much time is it going to
take away from him I'm like yeah so that
price has to go up cuz oh you hook me up
and no no no I can't hook you up and
take time away from my baby that's I
tell people that in meetings they're
like well I understand I said I thank
you if I do that for free I'm like my
baby doesn't eat so I rather just not do
it so Ricardo I don't mean to uh uh
interrupt there but uh we got commercial
break and then we'll be back this is
going good this is going far farther
than than I planned but this is awesome
so if you have more time I would love to
to pick your brain some more my time is
yours man I'll be here okay so if you
don't mind and put yourself on mute and
then we'll put
that a web design company in Calgary is
taking the concept of helping others to
a whole new level and as Robin Crawford
reports it was an Okanagan match who
inspired them to use their Tech skills
to help people with
disabilities it gives me a great
pleasure to introduce to you Michael D
Haynes a motivational speaker an
entrepreneur and a businessman Michael
Haynes is doing it all and I absolutely
love it it's the best job I've ever had
in the beginning hannes admits that he
didn't know how to get his customer
service Consulting business off the
ground and then he met Ryan Perez with
bowai creative for every website that we
sell we donate uh free websites to
entrepreneurs with disabilities the
Calgary based company builds websites
for businesses Haynes knew he needed a
website to promote himself and Perez
knew he had the tools to help we were
always talking about working um um in
the in or doing something for the
disability or for the for people with
disabilities um but we didn't know what
we were going to do and I thought that
this was a great time to um to do
something and and so we invented this
whole initiative like pretty much around
Michael bow tie creative built and
maintains an entire website for Haynes
free of charge he um put my ideas into
actions and that made my my
job so much easier oh it's an initiative
that the four-person company is proud of
it's especially close to pere's heart
because he himself has dyslexia I paved
my own path and that's why this this
this project means so much to me because
I want to help other people create their
paths bow tie creative is now helping
other people with mental and physical
challenges build websites across North
America all because of Michael Haynes
he's a great guy and it's fantastic
working with him and I can't wait to see
what happens next for him if you know um
anyone that has a mental or physical
disability that wants to become an
entrepreneur or you know needs to needs
help to get started in the right
direction definitely check out our
website Haynes hopes with the kind of
support offered by Perez and his team
more people will find the confidence to
reach their goals I have a challenge you
have a challenge there not person the
life with that
challenge I'm
my challeng is more pronounced than than
yours Robin Crawford Global News
Colona what's up Scott
yeah I was checking those out
mute that's why I could hear myself okay
sorry you guys couldn't hear
me uh let me try that again so I just
wanted to say uh just wanted to uh say
quickly hi to Scott Braun Patrick Andre
uh Matthew Johnston Tracy Craig wallette
uh Shirley Joseph Brandon Wilson thank
you guys for for hopping in uh uh Scott
Brun says luckily I don't have to do it
since she stays at home so I guess being
a
parent um he has a a wife that's taking
care of his kid at
home yeah that's that's the hardest job
in the world I tell you he
says yeah sorry I didn't mean to
interrupt you there uh dropping kids off
at the daycare is the ABS absolute worst
yeah it is but you know at the same time
I've grown to learned that you know the
kids don't remember all of that stuff
and it just I I got comfortable with it
because you know at the end of the day
uh it's about the quality of
time not the quantity of time it is so
totally is it's kids remember how you
make them feel uh so every time I'm with
him I try to make him feel special I
give him that
attention uh just make him secure he has
to know that
you know his dad is his Rock and I don't
care how far he goes or what he does
Daddy's got you and and it's it's worked
like he's amazing at daycare now and
just you drop him off and he like runs
to the other kids he's hugging everybody
and he's just a joy and a pleasure to be
around because I think he gets
emotionally that mommy and daddy aren't
going anywhere and I don't care how far
he goes or whether we leave or with
other people they come back they always
come back so yeah and speaking of which
you know uh when you were growing up
when did did you know from when you were
young that you would be an
entrepreneur that you would be even as
successful as you are
now two interesting questions uh did I
know I was going to be an
entrepreneur I've known since I was born
I'm
Different like I just I don't know what
had me believe that but from two three
years old I'm like yeah I I you know I
just had this this I don't know if it's
an attitude I like to call it commitment
you know a positive spin on that but
it's I've always known that I was
different I saw things differently you
know everybody's looking at one thing
and I'm like yo man you could make money
on that you know
[Music]
from and I don't know why I just I just
see the opportunity in things I'm like
oh it's just I look at this little toy
car and I'm like somebody is paying for
the paint there's a sticker on the side
there's plastic Wheels there's a mold
I'm like there's a lot of money making
these little cars I'm like you can get
in there and just do the paint on the
car and make and make make uh make money
on that so I'm I'm always looking at and
I'm the guy at the party counting the
heads to see how much the the the the
event planner made you know I'm like all
right all right you did a 20 grand
tonight I'm like that's not bad good for
you man you know I'm like that's what I
do when I go to a club I'm cting okay
okay but most those people got free but
they're buying alcohol all right that's
going to be a little trick like that's
what I do when I go outside I'm not
checking people but uh who were your
influences growing up like in terms of
business
like was it just you being different
and just being able to see things that
other people could see or did you also
have influences in your life where you
were uh my first business influence was
my
grandfather
um cuz I was apprenticing in his in his
shop to take over that business and it
was I would be there I would go down on
the weekends and do some work and I'd
see you know people coming in I'd see
how he charge money told me take this
clock up Park and I'm like well how do
you put it back together he goes like
just remember where everything went I
went it's a clock
dude have you ever taken a clock apart
and it's you know I'd love to take
things apart he's like yeah it's putting
it back together it's where you make the
money I was like so I got a clock and
got the works and cleaned it and took
the top off and remembered where all
those little dials went and you know I
put it back together and it was wrong
and had to have him help me and put the
brings like everything I'm like every
little piece was aart like hundreds of
these things and you have to put them
all back together in order and have the
clock work so I'd see that and learned I
would learn from him about value and
time and he would people would come in
and say yeah I could fix that watch for
you it'll be 100 bucks let's say and
I'll have it for you this afternoon he
goes but the guy across the street said
he could fix it for 50 bucks he goes
yeah he takes a
week he said well why don't you fix it
for 5050 bucks if it's an hour he goes
cuz I can do it in an hour doesn't mean
that's why it's worth more you can go
over there and wait a week it's 50 bucks
you said you're free to do it the guy
put his money down and walked out he
like good you went in the back you spend
five minutes fixing the watch he goes
when he comes in his watch is ready you
know what I'm like all right so it's I'm
learning that value gets created when
you're good I'm not you don't have to
work a long time uh coming to Canada
my first Mentor my first thing that
really taught me what to do was was pain
and
hunger I'm like I left home at
17 wasn't working for me I didn't want
to be there uh whole situation and uh
it's like I'm out I packed everything
into two garbage bags and I walked out
17 I was in grade 11 or 12 and uh I had
to eat and I was working at Hen zel's
packing boxes I was stock boy to this
day I love packing stuff and
uh it's I did the math I said if I'm
making you know 10 bucks an hour and I
work 40 hours a week and it's so much
time in the summer said I can't make
enough money to go to school so I
[Music]
quit it's like let's cut this short
right now so I quit I went to the
library got a book on how to paint
figure you can't get into too much
trouble painting and a friend of mine
uh we got together and started a
painting
company why did you leave the home again
like 17 years old you just thought it
was it or did you get into a fight or
like did something happen that
was yeah stuff happened um parents were
divorced my dad's remarried uh new wife
three kids no they're all
awesome
he's he's a difficult person to to to be
with he has sort of this Old West Indian
Iron Fist you know you're going to do it
my way or the highway and you know you
hit people and I didn't want to be hit
so I left
that's that's the most polite I could be
about
that well this is the hustle we're
pretty raw here I mean um I mean I don't
to be overly dramatic about it but it's
uh I didn't want to be hit I didn't want
to see people get hit it it it bothered
me and uh
after one night and one episode and I
was you know I was like yo this is
[ __ ] crazy and I put everything in
the garbage bag I looked my sister I
said yo I'm leaving and it was the first
time I saw snow it was a snowstorm I had
two Hefty garbage bags I just put my
stuff in it oh my God I went downstairs
I told him uh I said I'm leaving tonight
and he was like you can't leave my
house I said well okay I'll be going and
uh kissed my stepmom kissed the kids and
I said I love you all and uh you've been
great thank you for accepting me into
your
house and this is where I go
and I walked out into a
snowstorm that was it never went back
wow like
that I had to eat so I had to make money
I'm like when you do the math it doesn't
work you got to stop I mean it was end
up living down the street at a friend's
house sharing a bed with another dude
like they had three kids and then they
took me and my sister in and it
was I mean I love these people like
these people saved my life yeah like I
left like I'm new immigrant to the
country I've been here maybe six months
I had a jean jacket with that wool like
that cowboy sheep skin yeah was a little
crappy zear that was not a winter coat
and I I didn't know any better I'm from
Trinidad and I put that on I went out
into the snow and I I thought about that
day I'm like I could have froze to
death I was like what was I but I knew
what I didn't
want and anything else would have been
better
so he said if you leave my house don't
ever come back I said I have no
intention of coming back and I never
went
back
um and yeah went there shared a bed with
this dude for a year while we finished
grade 12 moved out got a little place
downtown
Ashawa and started Wasing living above a
crackhead like this guy would eat my
sausages that I would buy and like it
was insane like it was like I shopped at
Goodwill I would go in there and like
buy shirts for 25 cents and I'm going to
school every day and i' buy a mug and
there's this mug couldn't open so The
Jug for juice so you couldn't really
close it all the way so you had to all
this put it in halfway cuz if you put it
in all the way you can't open it so you
got to halfway with that jug and we had
one pot and like that's how I would cook
food and eat and go to grade 12 and
grade 13 like that's like people like I
went to the school that was quite it was
the most Posh school like all the rich
kids went there so people were everybody
wore Polo I'm shopping at Goodwill and
I'm like I'm wearing like a red acrylic
sweater you know what I mean I'm like
nothing cool about this I'm new to
Country and [ __ ] and I was like yo uh I
had this sense of pride and respect
in what I knew like my circumstances
didn't Define me and the fact that I was
wearing a red acrylic sweater while
everybody was wearing Polo and Roots
head to toe and driving their BMWs I was
like it just did not phase me because my
I knew what I had to do I'm like dude I
gotta go get
food like I'm not interested in your
Afterparty yeah and yeah so when I was
did the math at high enzel was the store
and then did uh started this
business rolled man like that you know
business partner ended up in lawsuits
like it was crazy I was 18 years old I
had 16 employees
hired all my friends paid them more than
minimum wage and you know he was
stealing money from the company and I
end up like walking away from it it was
like was a hot mess like there was no
guidance there was nobody to put some
Ricardo try this I was like hunger and
pain is what I was driving me to do this
stuff right but I learned a lot from
that experience went off to college went
off to University and uh when I got
there you know started following people
on YouTube like FUBU Damon
John
uh I would follow these
people religiously like anything I could
get I would read books and consume it
this is before Facebook and Twitter and
all these things were invented and I
would just like we went to school in
Windsor and it was right next to Detroit
so a lot of people would come to Detroit
and every chance I got I would take a
bus over to Detroit and go see them uh
they would be performing I've seen
Biggie and Tupac perform on the same
stage down there at this place called
the like like it's dude it's crazy but
it's it's it's I've met Rosa Parks like
it's crazy stuff has happened in my life
crazy like people hear about oh yeah
Ricard you met Rosa Parks or you know
you sued a record company in New York
and one and my wife the other day was
like laughing she goes that [ __ ] is real
I'm like and I was in a box and I'm like
yeah here's the judgment she's like you
weren't joking I'm like no I was like
what do you think I'm trying to
do I you know it was like got myself in
the hot water with black homecoming and
people not showing up and I spent all my
OSAP money on this concert and then I
was like I got nothing left so I might
as well sue you so I flew to New York
with a lawyer who did
nothing and I presented the whole case
like she just sat there I mean she's
awesome not to you know diminish what
she but I said who can present better
than me I'm like I know all the details
said I sat there we had a
judge Pete Rock and seal smooth partner
their lawyer was there the record
company and I they were like they were
completely unprepared cuz no one
expected a kid from Windsor who rides a
bicycle to fly to New York to sue you I
was like I was like good I like being
underestimated you don't know how hungry
I am I'm like they cut the lights off in
my house house dude you have all my own
money I'm coming to New York like that
type of like hunger like there were real
consequences if at all times if business
didn't go well I didn't
eat I couldn't go back to school so I
had to win so I had to prepare so I
would Johnny Cochran who was doing the
OJ Simpson case had come there and he
was doing a book signing I didn't have
any money to buy a book but I waited in
line and I wait like an hour and I would
come to him and he's like do you have
the book I said sir I do not have money
to buy your
book I said but I waited line to talk to
you to see if you give me a piece of
advice on how you win I said you win
every case like how do you do that he
said I out prepar the competition said I
make sure I'm
prepared I said Thank you took a picture
with
him and I went on I'll prepare a record
company and a major hip-hop artist and
win a lawsuit
because
like they cut the lights off in my house
like dude I was showering at the gym I
would stay at
school till the sun came up because
there was no heat in my house like they
oh you can't cut your heat off in Winter
I'm like trust me they could do
that they cut my telephone cuz the bill
was too high and they cut all my five
roommates phones they had nothing to do
with it but they were at the same
address they cut everybody's phone so
all my roommates hate me cuz all their
phones got cut because of my phone
bill wow yeah I'm
like there there were real consequences
for me at every stage and and only
looking back on life now do I understand
just how close to the edge I was at all
times like it wasn't to the edge for me
like working five jobs while I was going
to school and doing you know black
homecoming it was like that's what I got
to do to eat like yeah yeah I know I got
five jobs I'm like I'm cutting here
reing basketball games working in a bar
working as a teller at a bank I'm
like going to class and fighting with my
roommates when I get home I'm like and I
was just like yo I got stuff to do so I
got
this this Focus like I just lock stuff
out I just learn to just listen I know
it's hard but if if I'm not dead I can
fix this I'm always like that I'm like
yo it's it's I know we this is that onon
story from from my best friend who
passed in cancer we were living in
Toronto and things got tight you know
and we didn't pay our rent for a few
months the sheriff was coming to lock us
out we were there and the only thing we
had to eat for two weeks was one
onion it was it like it was a white
fridge you open it up it was like just
white it like there's nothing in there
but one onion we would just cut that
onion and put it on a hot dry Skillet
cuz we didn't have oil and we just toast
it and then eat inside ring outside ring
inside ring outside ring we go we'd
alternate and then after you eat your
slice of onion for the day you're like
I'll see you tomorrow two weeks and I
always say if I got more than an onion I
you can't beat
me wow like you you like you can't
beat like you can't get more Underdog
than that
yeah I'm what I got an onion I got
grapes
grapes grapes dude I got gra I got
sparkling water I'm like dude you can't
win so how did you express yourself
because I mean you going through all of
that cuz I mean that's what we call like
folks the hustle all that is the hustle
all like being in that grind grinding
those
gears making things happen even when you
are dealt with situations that are not
you know the most Pleasant
but that grinding gives you energy but
what was your release how did you
release that afterwards like being under
all that
pressure how did I release I didn't uh I
just kept going and going eventually I
broke um after a very
bad that was a crazy
relationship it was just uh it was
insane insane like
that was just insane anyway so after
that I was I came back to school and I
was like just a shell of a human
and then the roommates I'm living with
at that time were freaking out cuz they
human why did you go away for the summer
look I paid all my rent for the summer
and I'm out and we don't want to live
with you anymore so we packed up
everything you own and put it into
storage on the other side of town I was
like you did what
so I come back to like change locks and
I'm like Jesus but that moment is
when yeah I ended up going to therapy I
went to student counseling and I just
was like I need therapy and I have no
money I'm like somebody help
me they got me into this program and
they had students I'm like I and I was
just like talking to people my life and
what's going on and parents and school
like everything and they were just like
like the this student was not equipped
to deal with anything I was like she
just had to go hang on she was
conferencing with the professor at all
times and uh I was just I just needed a
release and just over months and months
of that therapy that was really my first
uh release of just like Ricardo you're
going to be all right
because of who you were and you know
like she reframed my scenario so I was
wasn't like just taking punches to the
face but just reframe that for me to
give me a little more mental strength
and that moved on and then years later I
went to extensive therapy and personal
development and training and reading
books on self-help and how to negotiate
and how to focus your mind like there's
the one thing we have tons of in this
house is books people come and go whoa
It's like a library I'm like yeah we we
do a lot of reading we have like
walls like 20 F feet long with
books um piles a pile of books 6 F feet
high like right over there
um we read a lot so it's like going
through a lot of that self-help taking
courses on personal development and how
to deal with stuff I took Landmark
Education was massive and having me deal
with a lot of putting my life back
together to move forward
um yeah man I highly recommend therapy
and personal development I still do it
to this day wow not not therapy but just
person just go back I'm like I'm dealing
with stuff I'm like there's no shame in
this it's your mental health this is
what you have this is The Equalizer
between all Humanity black white so your
your thoughts I I I guard my thoughts
and my very very closely like who I hang
out with who I talk
to can't be negative around me I have I
have had
enough you know I mean I know the impact
of that so I guard my space and my
mental space and my thoughts like almost
as much as my
baby when you look back now what would
you have told your younger self when he
left you know with the jean jacket and
the garbage bags what would you have
told him
it's going to be all right you're doing
the right
thing
uh yeah it wouldn't change
anything yeah yeah just kind of like
dude it's going to like I didn't know it
would be all
right and I would just be like buddy you
got this just that that Granny effect of
support like what I'm doing for my son
now is what I wish someone did and hope
someone did for me when I would you know
what I mean like you're looking like I I
go to high schools and I would talk to
kids and I see kids in grade 11 and
every time I'm like wow you're a child
and I'm like how irresponsible of adults
to allow someone that young who just
came to this country 6 months ago to
leave in a snowstorm like I was like
what what made that okay in your head
you know what I mean yeah like what made
you think that that was a good idea that
that's the right thing to do just let
him go he'll figure like like that's
lifethreatening right and it's highly
irresponsible um but when you're driven
by ego and pride you will do things that
are not from
Love and that will have you make choices
that
uh have dire consequences yeah so I try
to come from love in all of my choices
like I was dealing with a client the
other day and they weren't they didn't
pay me on time and I'm like getting all
upset it's Christmas and pay me my money
I'm like you know everybody gets into
that zone you know I'm was like you know
what Ricardo what you're going to do is
get up today and you're going to work on
that website you're going to make it
better and you're going to love them and
I just did for like two days I just went
on there and every time I updated
something or fix it I just kept sending
them updates like extra stuff that they
didn't pay for I'm like I'm just going
to keep doing more work you know what I
mean and here's my invoice and oh yeah
yeah I fixed this and I added some more
stuff and this wasn't really working
well so I upgraded it so it fixed better
and I changed it like I just kept loving
them yeah and they paid and everything
was good but the minute I start to get
into that you owe me something like
that's ego and it's like no Ricardo love
people yeah come from love come from
love because people are seeds and I even
for cuz I live in Alberta okay and
Alberta is going through a lot in terms
of um you know like in terms of the the
recession and um having to collect me
you know for the whole year just running
after people like y you owe me some
money and having to still but I've
learned how to be calm because it gets
emotional when money doesn't come in but
you realize like it doesn't matter like
you just have to keep yourself at a
steady Pace you got to keep your
emotions steady and people are like
seeds you got to continue to water them
because one one of these days those
seeds will grow you know I've I've also
learned how to do better coold calling
better you know trying to find other
ways of bringing in cash flow because if
I didn't do that man we wouldn't be
doing this podcast today but you know it
you know it just diversify your your
Revenue sources so
it's yeah yeah you know it's it's it's
tough but that's like folks this is what
this is again this is one of the best
hustles ones I've had so far because we
got really deep but it shows you like a
lot some some of us don't have those
stories but there are a lot of
entrepreneurs that share the same story
as Ricardo you know being put through so
much pressure but we all know what
happens when you put you know fossil
fuels through a lot of pressure or
carbon into a lot of pressure becomes a
diamond I mean a lot of us dream I had a
friend say I dream to be on
tedex and here here's a man that was on
there
and that's not even the you know what I
mean and he's still
going look look I'm G stop when I'm dead
like
that's like are you successful I'm like
man I I got plans you know I'm changing
up everything for 2017 and Beyond and
you know the way I'm looking at my life
right now is it's what can I do that
will impact my grandkids what can I do
to make sure that they're good because
I'm committed to stopping this cycle of
catch my ass in
in in life and family and all this stuff
like you know let's put pride and ego
and how what looks good aside and and
you know this this this type of cash
flow no man I'm setting myself up now so
that my grandkids will have something
not my kids my my kids
kids like that's how far out I'm looking
so I'm going to look out for them so
that and I'm sure in doing that I'm
going to get hand L I'm like I don't
need much you give me more than an onion
I'm up you know what I mean that's how I
look at my life I'm like I'm good I I
just keep it simple I'm like yeah if I
go with more onion I said yeah I was
winning I'm winning I just was like I'm
winning I was
like out of that experience we got this
i got this in I got this in life this
lesson you never have any problems
nobody has a problem and I'll tell you
why if you're
alive you can do something
to improve it fix
it and if you're dead it just got
solved
je so tell me what problem you have that
can be solved with either one of those
two
options you ain't got nobody has
problems you know that's a solid Point
yeah we have things that are
uncomfortable like I don't have food
like I got to go wait in line I ain't
got no money like I got ride a bike in
the winter time like go to five jobs
like that's uncomfortable like I don't
have food like I got to go wait and L
but would you rather do that or live
in New Delhi and be 5 years old and not
have no
family like there are no options at that
point that's hard what we're doing now
is uncomfortable there's heat I could go
to the Student Center during the during
the night play dominoes and sleep in the
corner and get up in the day when the
Suns out go back home shower at the gym
like it's uncomfortable to do that but
I'm still showering in hot
water still I still have a
bicycle I got more than onion I got this
you know me
like
like not to compare yourself to people
who have less who have more and this
type of stuff but but really understand
just how fortunate we all are to to live
here in North America if you're living
in North America
and you are at the bottom of the rank
you have it better than 95% of people on
this
planet in my worst day I was better off
than 95% of
humanity mhm you get what I'm saying
yeah so if I'm at the
top I better act like
it because all those people back there
need help you got to do something about
it mhm and if I don't make it work and I
don't find a way out of this I said
there's a lot of people behind me that
uh they're going to have it a lot worse
so I better figure this out mhm like
again getting away from what's happening
to me because that's all ego how do I
feel my personal Comfort level I can't
tell people I don't no money and like
that's just
ego every every entrepreneur goes to
that and it's like deal with it like if
you got to go do a lawsuit like okay
guess you're eating grapes for the next
couple weeks but you buy a plane ticket
go to New York like they got your money
like go get your money and
like go go get your money and win
against a record
company like at the end of it the lawyer
looked at me he was like wow he's like I
have never experience anything like that
like I had books of evidence I had
copies everything in triplicate and he
was like I want to postpone and we have
to fly back another day cuz they're
trying to have me fly back and I said
well you don't have to worry I made a
copy of everything for you here you go I
slid it across the table wow I was like
you could look at that on the
break we don't need to FedEx anything I
copied everything I have here you go
let's continue I researched the judge
I'm like who is this person what's their
life like do they have kids my age I was
trying to play every angle I'm like
because people are people
and hustle Zone you want to talk hustle
Zone like listen listen I I young people
come to oh I have it hard I have this I
said listen stop
it it's you don't have it
hard you don't I it just you have to
look at the world stop looking at your
current
circumstances you have to look at the
world cuz that's where you live you live
on the planet
and where could I put you in the world
that would be better than where you at
right now which
country should I put you in Russia you
want to go to
Kuwait you want to go to Syria those
places have it bad like people are
actually trying to kill you mhm like
it's uncomfortable whatever you're
dealing with it's like we use the wrong
terminology and it has us all screwed up
as if we can't solve the problem Oh is
racism and yeah yeah yeah I know that
yeah like [ __ ] that ain't
new you know what I mean and that can't
be an excuse for not doing something
have I encountered
racism
daily daily and have I encountered some
people who truly transformed and saved
my
life
daily like I had teachers when I was
working full-time taking care of my
brother and going to school 5 days a
week every night till mid night then
starting my day at 7:00 in the
morning I couldn't finish five paintings
for school or something like that and I
was like look I I like I did everything
I just I just can't she goes can't you
do it tomorrow I'm like I'm working I'm
doing this and she's like what would you
do and I told her what I would do and
she's like how do you feel if I give you
a B+ for all of that I said but I didn't
do the work she said I know but I'm just
going to give you the grade Ricard
because you actually can't do anymore
and I was like what are you talking
about I said I have to do the work to
get the grade I said if you give me an
extension for 2 weeks I think I could do
it she's like you're not listening to me
I'm going to give you the grade you
don't have to do it I know the quality
of work that you do and I know that if
you could do it you would have done it
and I believe you so I'm just going to
give you the grade I'm
like thank you like I show up on
somebody's door and knock on their house
with two garbage bags in the middle of a
snowstorm and they end up taking me in
to live with them right
these people what other people would
call quintal trailer park
rednecks like they delivered papers for
a living and they took in two kids me
and my sister in the middle of a
snowstorm wow
like and they had three kids already
have you spoke with them no I'm uh they
passed like we lost contact over the
years and runting to their kids on
Facebook years later and I was like
where's your mom and your dad I'm like
I'm coming over you know what I mean and
they were like yeah they both passed
like a few hour was like in tears oh my
cuz I couldn't tell them what what they
meant to me but like they smoke and
drank like fish
like imagine the worst case Simpsons
redneck like I love these
people love those like they saved my
life mhm and I've also been attacked in
the street and and a victim of a hate
crime with me and my wife like
I both like humanity is going to do what
it's going to do but I got stuff I got
to get done so I'm
not I'm not allowing any of that in man
I'm doing
me I love it I love I got my onion and
I'm good like I don't I don't need no CL
oh you don't like me I'm like I don't
need you to like me I like me you know
what I mean I'm like I am good and just
being learning to be centered from a
very early age
uh and
just just knowing their own truth and
walking in
it like regardless of the circum like
just I was as I said pain I had to do it
I'm like do you want to walk in your
truth or you want to get hit I'm like I
will walk in my
truth that's that's how it started like
I want to get
hit like
that's not to me I didn't want to get
into it and be all overly dramatic but
it's it's it's really uh oh this is
being broadcast on Facebook but it's
it's it's not even
um it's just real man
like everybody deals with stuff so but
you know and and I really appreciate you
disclosing on the hustle Zone you know
because it it honestly we all do I think
that's the that's this is the the the
goal of this show is to humanize the
entrepreneur re like
just because someone may be wealthy
millionaire or whatever it doesn't mean
they didn't go through the same things
that you went through however we just
have like as entrepreneurs we just have
different habits yeah we just choose to
to live life a different way so your
story is so important because all the
future entrepreneurs out there are going
to be like yeah man I got more than an
onion dude if you have more than an
onion I don't want to hear anything it
hurts I'm I'm like really eat an
onion no not not it's not a race to the
bottom but it's it's really about be
gratitude
and you know whenever you think things
are bad find a way to give like honestly
it'll it'll change your life like I
don't have anything I'm like go through
your closet pick out some clothes you
don't wear and send them to a
refugee like go volunteer your time in a
hospital go do something to give people
give back go I mean you do this with
with your work like every time you get a
site you're able to build one for
somebody with disabilities like that
that notion of giving back uh is
tremendously like reciprocity is
tremendously powerful yeah for yourself
like it's impossible to give a nut feel
good it just it just is so it's it's a
selfish thing you can do in helping
people but it really centers you of like
you know I am an abundant I have this
I'm about to go through everything in my
house and my life and I'm editing down
to what I use I'm like I'm going through
all this stuff all this stuff is going
to be gone in the New Year like I'm
going to be super I'm going minimalist
now I'm like I don't need stuff yeah you
know it's so funny I have what I need
and I'm good yeah I I uh the the the
gentleman that I helped with the website
uh and you know he's the one that got us
on the news and then all of a sudden he
came into some money and he's like Ryan
I'm cover to
Calgary like
what you covering to Calgary I mean like
he's like I'm coming to Calgary he made
the plans he rolls to Calgary and the
first thing he's like you know my my
assistant at the time he's like I'm
going to take you to the ceg cuz you
know when people have money they're like
I'm going to take you to the ceg right
so takes us to the cake treats us to
dinner yeah and then he says I want the
best website I want I want the best
website that you guys can provide me
because my my business needs to make
money mhm
and what he like I like the deal was
like I you know we got a deal but that
wasn't the the thing that mattered to me
the the the thing was that I I've been
hustling every day nonstop for a whole
year a year this time cuz I saw my dad
last year around this time and then when
I came back from seeing my dad all year
I've been non-stop in the same chair
same place you know other than taking
care of my son welcome to the hustle
Zone been
hustling but he was the first person to
take me you know and my my
assistant um to
dinner I haven't had like I haven't been
out anywhere with
anyone and and that to me was the best
thing that anyone could have done for me
because it was I didn't even celebate my
birthday Ricardo cuz I've been hustling
every single day and he you know just
said hey I'm coming to Calgary I wasn't
planning for I didn't plan for him to
come cuz I was like what is he doing
coming to calary like what's the I tell
you come to calary I tell you to come
but he took me to dinner and and it was
just like you know not that I couldn't
take myself to dinner it was just the
the fact that I for one hour was
a and then walked away with a deal and
so you never know who like you know you
never know who you help and how that
comes back to you but I didn't expect it
to come from him because I was willing
to give him everything yeah look if
you're
giving I believe like this give give
freely and and give and and actually
expect nothing back uh
and just give from your heart because
when you give from love it it just works
out like somebody gave me love at points
in my life I'm G pass this on this is
just good thing to do it's the right
thing to do just govern Yourself by that
like is this the right thing to do if it
is the right thing to
do do it yeah it's not may not be the
easy thing to
do but if it's the right thing to do you
should do it if you can like I'm not
saying give when you can can't but I'm
always like hey if I'm up from an onion
I can give you know yeah but I'll find
some way I'll point you in direction to
somebody else who can give more than I
can I say I'll connect you I'll talk to
you I'll do something but uh yeah man
just like people have been generous with
me from Johnny Cochran to Rosa Parks
like like Denzel Washington like all
kind it's like crazy like wow I tell
people in my life and they're just like
Ricardo that's [ __ ] like you're
lying
like what you mean you met Rosa Parks
I'm like yeah we had the same lawyer CU
I was suing Pete Rock and Seal's smoth
and like she came in like it's just
crazy this stuff that my life my whole
my life WR something like just crazy
like she's a short she's she was about
411 little lady I was like you so little
you CA all this she's like she's like
hello I'm like I didn't know whether to
stand up or salute or got there on a bus
you know what I mean I'm like holy
[ __ ] like you're the lady like you live
here in
Detroit wow it was it was like it's like
seeing Martin Luther King like walk
through the door you're like what
the like you only see people like that
in pictures yeah you don't expect you
know Barack Obama came knocking on your
door in two seconds you're like what the
like like it just blows your mind and
it's it's I thought she was passed but
she was alive and kicking there were
writing a book together wow and uh if
you look for her life story it's uh
what's his name his name is
Jeffrey had a very bombastic name
Jeffrey Reed was his name he was a
lawyer who co-wrote the book with her
about her life but yeah that was my
lawyer brother from Detroit I had a
junior lawyer we flew in to sued rocket
SES smoth like
it's and wow back on stuff I've done and
I'm like
wow that's a crazy resume man that's why
I respect you that's why you know I
really appreciate you coming on to the
hustle Zone I got a few more questions
before we go so first question is what's
your favorite
dessert cheesecake without a
doubt that's a good choice that's a good
choice uh without a doubt what makes you
happy loving my baby and my wife
what makes you
angry a lot of
stuff uh what makes me what gets me
angry like every time
is
uh very bad service like people who
don't care about the job that they're
doing and they just kind of no I'm up in
your bad shitty service day I'm like cuz
I I mean I like you know the impecc
ability of I've waited tables for years
and served people and like took care of
them so when I see people just giving
bad service whether it's a restaurant or
you come into a shop or like oh I'm at
zero to 100 man I'm like yo just give me
your apron just just sit down I got this
yeah that's not how you help people you
know bad service in anything I don't
care if it's corporate or if it's a
salad bad service bad service okay if
you had a
wand uh and you only had one wish what
would you use it
on I would
wish abundant
resilience and confidence for my
son
wow and why do you say
that cuz he's going to have more than an
onion and I don't want
to like I'm setting him up so he's a
millionaire yeah you know what I mean
and I'm like I don't want him to be one
of those trust fund kids that uh I mean
it's going to take a long time to get to
that point but yeah you know we planting
the seeds now and and it's
really I don't want to just take that
like the life I've lived and the
experiences I had was because of the
falls I've
had and I want him to be resilient like
I I don't want to catch him every time
he falls I want him to bruise his knees
a little bit and kind of yeah that's an
edge you shouldn't crawl off that you
know I don't want him to get hurt but I
want him to know that he is resilient
enough to to recover from climbing off
the couch and he'll be all right like
Daddy still loves you we got you when I
say take it
easy stuff could happen sometimes you
know so it's resilience that he
can come back from whatever is upsetting
him whether it's
mommy and daddy leaving him at day care
falling off a couch learning to
walk resilience like
that nobody could take that from you I'm
like if you're
resilient you go figure it a rest
out I give him an onion and slap him on
the back I say come on
buddy I can imagine when he gets older
SE this is an onion it's onion I live I
mean it's probably gonna mean nothing to
him I think about that I'm like
it's these are just going to sound like
crazy stories old grandpa is talking
about you know what I mean like it's
it's it's not even going to be relevant
to his life yeah and but what I keep
thinking about and
Distilling is what is the essence of the
story what is the point of that
experience and how do I duplicate or
create an opportunity for that lesson or
experience in his life for his own way
so that it's not you don't have to do
what I did like you just have to you
have to do you but resilience like in
whatever it is that he wants to
do yeah it's it's it's it's not about me
anymore man my grandkids just your
grandkid when I get you know a few years
down the road you know I saw this on
Steve Harvey's like look put aside 1500
bucks and some gicc for your grandkids
he said you don't know what's going to
happen in a 100 years with that money
like it could be million bucks when you
turn 25 here you go yeah like sure who's
who's Grandpa Ricardo like somebody was
thinking of me like yep yep Grandpa
Ricardo was thinking of you like you
know what I mean that's amazing it's
it's I I look real far out it it has me
overlooked my circumstances my
discomfort my okay we're not doing that
anymore I can't do this I'm like it's
all that stuff I'm looking way way I
have my head up man yeah so yes so we
are done so thank you so much uh for for
for hopping into the hustle zone so how
how was your experience with the hustle
Zone this is brilliant man this is this
is hot this is hot this is going to be
uh don't miss it this is the hustle Zone
if you miss it
it's you got
problems but so I got to ask you one
more thing before you leave um it's a
call and response so when I say welcome
to the
I need you
to yell it out without waking up your
baby I understand baby sleeping I
will so welcome to the hustle
Zone come on people get to
it all right thank you so much and where
can we find you Ricardo you can connect
with me uh on Twitter at Ricardo McCrae
it's the easiest place to reach out or
Instagram I'm on both of those platforms
a lot and uh yeah just if you don't want
to do that Google me see what comes
up all right thank you so much my friend
and you're welcome thank you for having
me on this has been a pleasure to be
able to share a bit of my story in my
life and I hope it makes a difference
for some people and people can benefit
from it so it sure for creating the
platform man we got a lot of people in
in and we got a lot of comments today
which was great um oh cool so uh Anna
says thank you for hosting this Ryan
keep that sound bite uh Ryan that is
money I appreciate that some is better
than an onion you know
yeah and then Anna says I'm never going
back to an onion the same way
again an onion is extremely nutritious I
tell you right
now okay so Anna says fall down seven
times get back up eight
that's right I love it and then uh
William
William uh I don't's up will yeah you
know will Will's like I never have seen
I've heard that story I never seen no
yeah I've never have since I've heard
that story yeah cuz I think he was in
remember we were in that broadcast I
think he was in that yeah right with um
kente yeah and we were both on that and
we got into your life so let me ask you
a question when you coming on my framing
podcast sir you you got to invite me sir
I'm I'm down I have to invite you dude
you running things man I'm like you have
to grace me with your present all right
I'll send you I would I would love to
love to be a part of it thank you I will
send you a link to to pick your favorite
day and uh we'll do it man we'll I will
return the favor for sure got to have
the the the Ryan with a little respect
on it
that's that's me and you know what that
is yeah we know that yeah put some
respect on my name when you talk
you oh man this has been beautiful thank
you for the opportunity yeah no problem
and and and U say hi to baby say hi
Gloria H and then say hi to the hawk for
me I I love that Hawk
man I was so drawn in cuz you're like
see look at him he's going after the
squirrel but he missed oh he's back and
then I'm like get inside get inside
what's going on you cra over my head he
was like huge he was like right there I
mean who sees a hawk like 10 feet away
from a squirrel and the squirrels
getting like it was this was crocodile d
d in the middle of the city man this was
the best like I love animals I'm always
watching those Nature Documentaries so
I'm like my wife is just like she's
messaging me on on Facebook in the
middle of it she goes shouldn't you be
working I'm like get out of here I'm
looking at
him and then the funny part man just
drawing a circle you're like look right
there that hog right there that's a hog
right there that's a squirrel that
squirrel doesn't give two shits
like that squirrel was like a foot away
from the HW was like I'm like oh man I
need a telephoto
lens well anyway thank you so much and
uh f folks make sure to again name is
Ryan Perez owner and founder of bch
creative for every website we sell we
donate free websites to entrepreneurs
with disabilities if you know someone
that's in need that wants to get to the
next level but don't have the the
capital to do so get them to hit me up
I'll get them to sign up our uh to sign
up on our uh our waiting list and yeah
and folks this is the hustle so we're
going to have a a magazine is coming out
like I'm almost done I'm pumped about it
so we're going to have we're going to
ask uh folks like uh Gloria and Ricardo
and all the entrepreneurs to write
articles uh it's peer-to-peer mentoring
peer-to-peer sharing so it's just a
whole new uh phase to media and uh not
that I'm not saying that I invented it
but it's just what's happening with
Facebook live we're all just coaching
each other so we're loving it you know
so it's just a new Leading Edge we're
making it happen we're doing it that's
right so